（走过的路）
我会救回我哥哥的 至死方休
I will save my brother or die trying.
这是该隐的血印
It's the mark of Cain.
那就是个诅咒 是能去除的
It's just a curse. It can be removed.
- 你是他们的走狗 - 出去
- You're their bitch. - Get out.
《诅咒之书》是一本咒语书
"The book of the damned" is a spell book.
是用来创造或解开所有诅咒的
for creating or undoing any kind of damnation there is.
我觉得这是密文
I think this is in code.
把娜迪娅的法典拿来给我
Bring me Nadya's codex,
我马上就能破解密文
and I'll break this text right open.
迪恩的情况并没好转
Dean is not getting any better.
我们如果不祛除血印
If we don't get the mark off his arm,
他会被吞噬的
it's gonna eat him up.
我的能量 已经恢复了
My grace, it's been restored.
为我哥哥找到治愈办法 我会杀死克劳力
Find me a cure for my brother. Then I'll kill Crowley.
谢谢你 萨姆 让我记起了我究竟是谁
So, thank you, Sam, for reminding me who I really am.
她一定还有什么我不知道的秘密
There must be something that I don't know about her,
可以让我用作筹码的
something I could hold over her as a bargaining chip.
她破解了密码
She's cracked the code.
查理
Charlie?
我不想迫不得已伤害你
I don't want to have to hurt you.
我觉得这不是个问题
I don't think that's gonna be a problem.
（如今）
（萨姆 没法多说 下载文件 为了迪恩）
有消息吗
Anything?
12通留言
12 voicemails.
宝贝车上的跟踪器显然是被解除了
Lojack on the Impala has clearly been disabled.
所以什么线索都没有
So a big heaping scoop of nothing.
我们需要罗威娜马上兑现承诺
We need Rowena to hold up her end of the bargain… now.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing. It's…
如果她用《诅咒之书》去除了血印
it's just if she removes the mark using "The Book of the Damned"…
后果要怎么办
What of the consequences?
什么后果
Which are what?
- 迪恩说… - 那是他猜的
- Dean said… - Dean guessed!
小卡
Cass.
我们还能怎么办
What are we supposed to do, huh?
坐以待毙吗
Just sit on our asses, do nothing?
不 我们找到迪恩
No. We find Dean.
然后呢
And then what?!
唯一阻止了该隐的 是死亡
The only thing that stopped Cain was death.
你想杀了迪恩吗 我可不想
Do you want to kill Dean? Because I don't.
而我所知道
And the only way I know.
唯一能救我哥哥的办法就是去除血印
how to save my brother is to cure the mark.
是啊 我知道会有后果的
And, yes, I know there will be consequences,
但你 迪恩
but not you, not Dean…
谁都说不出会有什么后果
not anybody can tell me what those consequences are.
所以我不会让我哥哥为了说不好的事自毁
So I'm not gonna let my brother d-destroy himself on a guess.
我们得救迪恩
We save Dean.
（萨姆的12通留言）
我没事
I'm good.
[邪恶力量 第10季第23集]
罗斯·麦金利
Rose McKinley.
在离这里三英里处长大
Raised up about three miles from here.
父母人很好 很虔诚
Nice parents, god-fearin' folk.
那还让她穿得像个妓女似的出门
Well, they let her leave the house looking like a whore.
把真实想法说出来吧 探员
Why don't you tell me what you really think, agent?
抱歉 治安官 是我不好
Oh, I'm sorry, sheriff. My bad.
告诉你我们这里的规矩吧
Let me tell you how we work out here, son.
就算她是巴比伦的淫妇
That right there could be the Whore of Babylon…
也无所谓
wouldn't make no difference at all.
因为在我眼里 她是好人家的女儿
'cause all I see is somebody's little girl.
我不该乱说话 治安官
And I feel like a real jerk suggesting otherwise, sheriff.
对不起
My apologies.
你这么盲目 祝你能破案了
Good luck crackin' the case with your eyes shut.
你遇到过些挺糟心的案子吧 探员
You worked some pretty dark stuff in your day, haven't you, agent?
肯定留下了很深的印记
Must've left quite a mark.
你都想不到
Oh, you have no idea.
你搭档真不是省油灯 探员
Your partner's a piece of work, agent.
可不是
Yeah, ain't he, though?
迪恩
Dean-o!
欢迎加入
Welcome to the party.
你来干什么 鲁迪
The hell you doing here, Rudy?
我就是喜欢死妹子
Ah, you know, just a thing I got for dead girls.
查一群吸血鬼
Just… just workin' a gang of fang, you know?
跟你一样
Just like you.
今天不行
Yeah, not today you're not.
这事你别管了
I'm gonna need you to take a walk on this one.
好吧 但是 是我叫你来的
Uh, okay, except, uh… except I called you,
如果说有谁该别管
so, uh, if anybody's walking, it's…
你叫我来的 不对 是你求我来的
Oh, you called me? No, no. You begged me.
在塔斯卡卢拉萨 老莱姆镇也都是这样
Just like Tuscaloosa, just like Old Lyme,
我们都知道你就是在装样子
we both know you're playing dress-up out here,
你迟早会害死自己的
and it's just a matter of time before you get yourself killed.
所以你听我的 别管了
So why don't you take that walk.
- 让真正的好猎人干活儿吧 - 探员
- and let the real hunters do the work? - Agents!
新情况
New deal.
罗斯失踪时不是单独一人
Rose wasn't alone when she disappeared.
朋友克丽丝托·索森也跟她在一起
Friend named Crystal Thorrson was with her,
克丽丝托依然不见踪影
and Crystal is still awol.
我这就去跟她父母谈谈
I'm heading over to interview the parents.
你们就别跟去了
How about we agree you boys sit this one out?
知道吗
You know something?
人生苦短 搭档
Life's too short… partner.
我不管你今天是怎么了
You know, I don't know what crawled up your ass today,
老实说 我不在乎
but frankly, I don't care.
带我跟你弟弟问好
Regards to your brother.
好啊 两位
Hello, boys.
正好赶上喝茶 除非你们有别的心事
Just in time for tea… u-unless something on your mind?
其实 有五颗
Five things, actually.
空心弹 内含能杀死女巫的药剂
Hollow tips filled with witch-killing brew.
真刺激啊
How exciting for you.
你们步枪协会要骄傲得不能自己了
Your NRA will be beside themselves with pride.
别再玩游戏了 罗威娜
No more games, Rowena.
马上施咒
Do the spell now.
否则呢
Or what exactly?
得了 萨穆埃尔
Come on, Samuel!
你和我都知道你就是在虚张声势
You and I both know that's nothing but a bluff.
查理虽然破解了法典
Charlie may have cracked the codex,
但我如果不在了 谁会给你解读呢
but who's going to read it if I'm gone?
再加上调配原料
Not to mention handling the ingredients,
拿捏剂量
getting the measurements just right…
除非你俩
Unless, of course, either of you.
曾花数年时间 跟大师学习
have spent years of your life studying with the greats,
掌握高级巫术的技巧
mastering the intricacies of high witchcraft?
抱歉 或许你俩真学过呢
But forgive me. Maybe you have.
我知道你不高兴
I know you're upset.
我们都一样
We all are.
可怜的迪恩啊
Poor Dean.
我们来喝杯茶吧
Let's just have a nice wee cup of tea…
好好商量一下
and negotiate.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
这个嘛
Oh, well,
我们都知道我想要什么
we know what I wanted.
但这事没办成 是吧
Soiled the sheets on that one, didn't we?
我们说说我愿接受什么吧
Let's talk about what I'll take…
给我自由
my freedom guaranteed.
和法典
and the codex.
萨姆 你不能
Sam, you can't be…
你知道是什么咒语吗
Do you know which spell?
是的
I do.
萨姆
Sam.
这是个错误
This is a mistake.
罗斯和克丽丝托一直是
Rose and Crystal were friends since…
好朋友
forever it seems.
你觉得克丽丝托可能还有危险吗
Uh, you think that Crystal could still be in danger?
是的 麦金利太太 找到克丽丝托最快的办法
We do, Mrs. McKinley, and the fastest way to find Crystal.
就是找到杀罗斯的凶手
is to find out who did this to Rose.
你们注意到她最近行为是否有异常吗
Did you notice any change in her behavior recently…
新交什么朋友 男朋友没有 或许喜欢上谁了
Uh, new friends, a new boyfriend, maybe a crush?
罗斯很害羞的
Rose was…a shy girl.
你觉得她可能认识害死她的人吗
But…you think she might know who did this to her?
罗斯不仅认识那人
In Rose's case, she not only knew the person,
还想跟那人交媾呢
but, uh, she was trying to have intercourse with them.
所以我想查清究竟是男友
So I'm just trying to figure out whether it was a boyfriend.
还是随便在草垛上滚的人
or whether it was just some random roll in the hay.
没有
No.
据我们所知 她没有男友
Uh, there were no relations that we're aware of.
根本没有这种事 你什么意思 探员
No relations at all. What the hell is this, agent?
我只是在尽职 麦金利先生
I'm just doing my job, Mr. McKinley.
就说我女儿是个荡妇吗
By suggesting my daughter was a slut?
我承认 我这么想过
I'll admit that thought crossed my mind.
但我来到这里 闻到了这家里
Then I came here, and I smelled the deceit.
欺骗 虐待 和耻辱的气味
and the beatings and the shame that pervade this home.
知道吗 我不再怪罗斯了
And you know what? I don't blame Rose anymore.
- 你闭嘴 - 怪不得她穿得那么浪荡
- You shut your face right now. - No wonder she put on that skank outfit.
出去寻求他人的认可
and went out there looking for validation,
落进了杀害她的怪物的怀中
right into the arms of the monster that killed her.
乔 是谁干的
Joe, who did this?
- 不 - 乔
- No! - Joe!
- 是谁干的 - 住手
- Who did this? - Stop!
乔
Joe.
是谁干的
Who did this?
我不知道
I don't know.
I don't know!
干什么
What?
克丽丝托 她…
Crystal, she's still…
怎么了
Why?
十字溪那边有几个人
There were these guys living out by Cross Creek,
说他们在翻修那边的一栋屋子
said they were rehabbing a cabin out there.
我觉得他们就是想要个喝酒约妹子的地方
Mostly, I think they just wanted a place to drink and meet girls.
克丽丝托和你姐姐认识他们
And Crystal and your sister knew these guys?
可你姐姐死的时候
But you couldn't be bothered to tell the cops that.
你却没跟警察说吗
when your sister turned up dead?
当初就是我带她们去那里的
I was sort of the one who brought them out there in the first place.
[咒语]
「上帝所造 人类禁用」
"S-something made by God, but forbidden to man."
禁用
Forbidden?
禁果吗
The forbidden fruit?
不会吧
No.
苹果是第一道原料吗
The actual apple is the first ingredient?
[咒语]
好吧 接下来呢
Okay, uh, what's next?
「人类所造 上帝所禁」
"Something made by man, but forbidden by god."
上帝禁止伪神 是吧
Okay, well, god forbade false idols, right?
金牛犊
The golden calf.
那东西不是毁了吗
Wasn't that destroyed?
[咒语]
这可好
Great.
第三样是什么
What's the third ingredient?
怎么了
What?
第三样 不可能拿到
The third ingredient, it's impossible.
是什么
What is it?
大意就是 我的心
Loosely translated… my heart.
这没什么不可能
It's not impossible at all.
不是真指我的心脏 小小鸟
Not my literal heart, feathers.
是我爱的东西 咒语要我杀我所爱
Something I love, the spell calls for me to kill it.
- 血祭 - 是的
- A sacrifice. - Precisely.
书可以解除咒语
The book will grant freedom from the curse,
但要有所回报
but it wants something in return.
那就献出啊
Well, then give it.
拿个我爱的东西来 我肯定杀
Bring me something I love, I'll kill it.
我太想要自由了 不会心软的
I want my freedom too much to make a fuss over that.
问题就是 我不爱任何东西
The… the problem is, I don't love anything.
那克劳力呢
What about Crowley?
我很乐意杀了他 不算是爱了
Happy to kill him. Let's not call it love.
我不信
I don't believe you.
人人都有所爱
Everyone loves something.
奥斯卡
Oskar!
吃饭了
Czas na kolacje!
波兰男孩 奥斯卡
Polish boy. Oskar.
什么 奥斯卡
I'm sorry. Oskar?
你看到了奥斯卡
You saw oskar?
他是谁
Who is he?
他早死了 是个农民的孩子
Who was he? Uh, a peasant boy…
他家人帮我度过了一段难关
his family helped me through some difficulties.
那是三百年前了
300 years ago.
鲁迪 什么事
Rudy. What's up?
真想告诉你是好消息 萨姆
Wish I could say it was good news, Sam.
我刚刚遇到了迪恩
I just bumped into Dean.
在苏佩里尔查一宗吸血鬼案
working a fangbanger case in Superior.
迪恩在内布拉斯加查案吗
Dean's in Nebraska, w-working a case?
嗯 我的案子
Yeah, my case.
而且
And, uh…
他跟人处得很不愉快
He's not playing well with others.
嗯 迪恩现在状况不太好
Yeah, Dean's not exactly in the best place right now.
帮个忙
You know what? Do me a favor.
把具体情况发短信给我 好吗
Just text me the details, would you?
好 都听你的
All right. Whatever you need.
好 谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
怎么了
What's going on?
小卡 拿着
Cass, take this.
这是迪恩的头发 你得用这个完成咒语
It's Dean's hair. You need it for the spell.
小卡 你得帮我这个忙
Cass, I need you to do this for me.
无论付出什么代价 一定完成咒语 求你
Make the spell happen whatever it takes, please.
迪恩 这是雷吉
Dean-o, uh, this is Reggie.
我们就好好谈谈
We're just gonna talk, all right?
达成共识
And… and come to an understanding.
给我出去 先生
Back your ass out of the room, mister,
把刀留下
and leave the blade.
嗯
Yeah.
休想
No.
鲁迪 走开吧
Rudy, walk away.
迪恩 别啊
No, d… no, d-Dean-o,
按他说的做吧
Just do what he says, okay?
他才不会杀你呢
He's not gonna kill you.
你是他的筹码
You're his insurance, all right?
像个男人样 走开
Now man the hell up and walk away.
我会杀他的 朋友
Oh, I will kill him, friend.
你再废话 我就杀了他
You keep yappin', I will.
- 动手啊 - 迪恩
- Do it. - Dean!
- 退后 - 动手啊
- Back up. - Do it.
别逼我
D-don't test me.
迪恩 别走了
Dean, stop!
你根本没这胆
You don't have the guts.
你做了什么啊
What did you do?!
你是克丽丝托吧
You're Crystal, right?
好吧
Yeah, well…
我刚刚救了你
I just rescued you.
他…你本可以好好谈的
He… you could've talked.
你…
You just…
不客气
You're welcome.
（汽车旅馆）
他就让他死了
He just let him die.
Just let him die.
探员
Agent.
或许你能告诉我到底是怎么回事
Maybe you can tell me what in the hell is going on here.
按外面那女孩的说法
The way the girl outside tells it.
你们一位探员冲进来了
Is one of your boys came in hot,
把他的搭档害死了
got his partner killed,
然后像个日本武士一样把那混蛋杀了
then went some kind of samurai on that son of a bitch over there.
我认识那孩子
I knew that boy…
如今谁还用这招啊
Who summons anymore?
就不能打电话吗
Couldn't you call?
我手机里没有你电话
You're not in my contacts list.
干什么
What?
我需要你帮忙
I need your assistance.
去除迪恩的血印
to help cure Dean of the mark.
那话怎么说的来着 我帮过了
What's the expression I gave at the office?
如果萨姆·温彻斯特不是
Maybe I'd feel a little different.
才试图杀我 我或许还愿意帮忙
if Sam Winchester hadn't just tried to bloody kill me!
恐怕 我不接受拒绝
I'm afraid "no" is not an acceptable answer.
否则呢
Or what?
否则
Or…
好啊
That's right.
点亮蓝眼睛吧
Burn those eyes blue.
张开残破的小翅膀 灭了我吧
Spread those broken wings and destroy me!
否则 按我的来
Or…do it my way.
这就对了
Right.
求我
Now beg.
什么
What?
炸我 要么就求我
Blast me, or beg.
- 克劳力 - 叫我国王陛下
- Crowley. - King!
国王陛下
King.
劳烦您
If you… if you would…
劳烦您 好心帮个忙
if you would be so kind…
这清单上的三个原料
The three ingredients on this list.
「禁果」
"Forbidden fruit."
首先
Well, for starters,
那是柑橘 你个傻蛋 不是苹果
it's a quince, you dummy, not an apple.
没问题
No problem.
金牛犊 至少是留存下来的残骸
"Golden calf"… or what's left of it…
没问题
Check.
「罗威娜所爱之物」
"Something Rowena loves"?
我本以为是你 但是…
I would've thought it would've been you, but…
得了 我试过了
Spare me. I've lived it.
怎么样
Well…
我加入
I'm in.
迪恩 是我
Dean, it's me.
（宝贝给你了）
[咒语]
那不是干酪吧
Don't tell me that's queso.
是啊
Yeah… yes.
干酪
Queso and, uh,
小玉米卷 玉米粉蒸肉
taquitos, tamales.
都是我亲手做的
Homemade by yours truly.
肥得流油
All with the bad fat.
就当是献祭吧
Consider it an offering.
为了什么
For?
我要你杀我
I want you to kill me.
我觉得十分有趣的是 迪恩
What I find truly fascinating, Dean.
手艺不错
That's good.
你我都知道
…is that you and I both know…
我以前被你们温家人坑过
that I've been burned by you Winchesters before,
你居然还敢召唤我
yet you still call.
我知道 这次不会了
Yeah, I know, but not this time, okay?
不会耍诈 不会反悔
No games, no second thoughts.
你知道这是什么
I know you know what this is.
你知道它的能耐
I know you know what it can do.
我努力想克制
I've tried to fight it.
我想自己抵抗它
I've tried to beat it on my own.
但我做不到
And I-I can't.
我已经没招了 只剩你了
I got no moves left… except you.
真没想到还能有这一天
Well, I never thought I'd see the day.
天呐
My goodness.
迪恩·温彻斯特也末路穷途了
Dean Winchester has tipped over his king.
但我不会杀你 迪恩
But I won't kill you, Dean.
你是死神
You're death.
而你胳膊上的血印是第一道诅咒
And that mark on your arm is the first curse.
没什么能杀了你
Nothing can kill you.
好吧 那别管杀我了 你能去掉它吗
Okay, well, forget killing me. Can you get rid of it?
我可以
I could.
但是呢
But…
从无到有
Creatio ex nihilo…
上帝从虚无中创造了世界
God created the earth out of nothing…
至少你们主日学校的老师是这么教的
or so your Sunday-school teacher would have you believe.
那么《创世纪》是骗人的喽
What, so Genesis is a lie, eh?
令人震惊
Shocker.
有光之前
Before there was light,
有上帝和大天使之前
before there was God and the archangels,
世界并非虚无的
there wasn't nothing.
世界有黑暗
There was the darkness,
破坏力很强
a horribly destructive,
毫无道德的力量 它被上帝和大天使击溃了
amoral force that was beaten back by God and his archangels.
那是场可怕的战争
in a terrible war.
上帝把黑暗锁在它无法肆虐的地方
God locked the darkness away where it could do no harm,
他创造了一个血印
and he created a mark.
血印既是锁也是钥匙
that would serve as both lock and key,
他将此托付给他最信任的副手 路西法
which he entrusted to his most valued lieutenant, Lucifer.
但血印开始产生了自己的想法
But the mark began to assert its own will,
变成了一个诅咒 开始败坏
revealed itself as a curse, and began to corrupt.
路西法开始嫉妒人类
Lucifer became jealous of man.
上帝把路西法逐下地狱
God banished Lucifer to hell.
路西法把血印传递给了该隐
Lucifer passed the mark to Cain,
而他又把血印传递给了你
who passed the mark to you,
也就是所说的 以一人命换天下
the proverbial finger in the dike.
真是棒极了
Well, that is just fan-friggin-tastic, isn't it?
我可以去除血印
So I could remove the mark,
但你必须把它传下去
but only if you will share it with another.
以保证锁不被打破
to ensure that the lock remains unbroken.
黑暗不会被放进来
and the darkness remains banned.
不行
I'm not doing that…
我不能这样对任何人
not to anyone.
那如果我可以送你去别的地方
What if I told you I could relocate you somewhere far away,
甚至不是在这星球上
not even on this earth,
你可以继续活着
where you would still be alive,
但不会再对你自己和他人构成威胁呢
but no longer a danger to yourself or to others?
迪恩
Dean.
我试过了 萨姆
I gave it a shot, Sammy.
听我说 不管你要做什么
Listen to me… whatever you're doing,
不管你做了什么 求你
whatever you've done, please…
我都去查案了
Hell, I even worked a case.
我已经拼尽全力 想抵住它
I gave everything I had to beat this thing down.
我看到了 我看见鲁迪了
I saw. I saw Rudy.
那你看见我干的混蛋事了
Well, then, you saw what I did.
那不是你
No, that wasn't you.
感觉就是我
Sure as hell felt like me.
弟弟 我完了
Brother, I'm done.
不 你没有 迪恩
No. No, you're not. Dean.
找支笔记下来 该道别了
Grab a pen. It's time to say goodbye.
我给你满上 吉米
Get you a refill, Jimmy.
想听故事吗
Fancy a story?
是你
You?
你干了什么
What did you do?
很久很久以前
A long, long time ago,
有一位邪恶贱人 抱歉 是邪恶女巫
there once lived an evil bitch … sorry, witch …
她被迫背井离乡 抛下她唯一的儿子
who was forced to flee her home and her only son.
因为她实在太坏了
because she was, well, horrible.
她饥肠辘辘 无家可归
Starving and homeless,
于是向波兰的一家农民求助
she threw herself upon the mercy of a peasant Polish family.
他们收留了她 给她食物
who took her in, fed her,
让她恢复了体力
and nursed her back to full strength.
这是一种她不曾体会过的善意
This was a kindness she had never known.
她尤其喜欢那个8岁的小男孩
She was particularly taken by their 8-year-old son.
并渐渐对他萌生爱意
who, apparently, she grew to love.
你怎么会知道这些的
How do you know all this?
一只仓鼠告诉我的
A hamster told me.
但可悲的是
Tragically…
这个男孩得了绝症 很快就要死了
…the boy was terminally ill and soon to die.
但女巫离开之前
But before the witch departed,
她给了这男孩和他们一家
she gave the boy and his family.
唯一的也是最好的报答
the only thanks that made sense.
她用一个咒语治愈了这孩子
She cured the boy with one spell.
还施了一个等他成年后才会生效的永久咒
and cast another that would take root once he was full-grown.
我那个满口谎话 爱操纵人的贱人母亲
That lying, manipulative whore mother of mine.
给了你永生 是吧 奥斯卡
gave you immortality, didn't she…Oskar?
萨姆
Sam.
这是怎么回事
What is this?
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
无论你现在想干什么 停下
Whatever you are thinking of doing, don't.
还有别的办法的
There is another way.
你不必和他走的 你不必死的
You don't need to go with him. You don't need to die!
你这么说真有意思
Funny you say that.
其实 我离开时
Truth is, when I left,
我以为唯一的办法就是我去死
I thought the only way out was my death.
但我错了 萨姆
Well, I was wrong, Sam.
是你得死
It's yours.
什么 他要…
What? He's gonna…
把你送去外太空吗
gonna send you into outer space?
他可没说外太空
No, well, he didn't say outer space.
这简直疯了 迪恩
This is madness, Dean!
根本不疯狂
Far from it, I'm afraid.
- 没人问你 - 听他说完
- No one's asking you. - Hear him out!
这个困境很简单 萨姆
Our conundrum is simple, Sam.
你哥哥杀不死
Your brother cannot be killed,
血印也消不掉
and the mark cannot be destroyed,
否则会释放出我们无法想象的
not without inciting a far greater evil.
更邪恶的力量
than any of us have ever known.
什么邪恶力量
What evil?
黑暗
The darkness.
那是什么鬼
What the hell is that?
你觉得呢
Well, what does it sound like?
听着是好东西吗
Does it sound like a good thing?
即使我把迪恩送走
Even if I remove Dean from the playing field,
但还有你 忠心耿耿 死心塌地的萨姆
we're still left with you, loyal, dogged Sam,
一定不会善罢甘休
who I suspect will never rest.
一定会努力解救哥哥
until he sets his brother free …
不帮哥哥摆脱血印 绝不会停手
will never rest until his brother is free of the mark,
但那样一来
which simply cannot happen,
黑暗也会被释放
lest the darkness be set free.
再加上你之前放我鸽子
Then there was that time you stood me up.
你用我的命做了交易
You traded my life.
只要能保证我和这玩意
I'm willing to live with this thing forever,
永远无法伤害到别人
as long as I know that I and it.
我愿意一直这样活着
will never hurt another living thing.
这不是你
This isn't you.
这没道理
This doesn't make any sense.
不 这完全有道理
No, it makes perfect sense.
你就是太自私 才想不通
if you stop thinking about yourself for one damn minute!
这是为大局着想
It's for the greater good.
你如果能考虑大局
Once you consider that,
也就能想通了
this makes all the sense in the world.
怎么都拉长着脸
Why the long faces?
我猜猜
Let me guess.
妈妈又只给你看 不让你摸了
Mother showed you her "mustn't touch it" again.
拿到原料了吗
Do you have the ingredients?
柑橘让我欠了一个巴勒斯坦术士一个大人情
The quince cost me a major I.O.U. with a Palestinian warlock.
牛犊的金块
The gold from the calf …
如果我下次再去约旦
well, let's just say I'll be hanged.
就会因有伤风化罪
under certain sexual-deviancy laws.
被绞死
if I ever show my face in Jordan again.
第三样呢
And the third?
是啊
Ah, yes.
在我漫长的一生中 我都在想
All my long life, I wondered.
我究竟做了什么会让母亲不爱我
what I'd done to deserve a mother who refused to show love.
我为此痛苦
I pained over it.
以此建立了自己的王国
I built my bloody kingdom on top of it.
直到有一天 我醍醐灌顶
Then one day, epiphany struck.
我母亲根本不会爱任何东西
My mother was incapable of loving anything.
几百年来头一遭
For the first time in hundreds of years,
我感觉自由了
I felt free.
然后你出现在我的地牢里
And then you showed up in my dungeon,
我们谈心
we communed,
我开始意识到你并非不能去爱
and I began to realize you weren't incapable of love.
你只是不能爱我
You're incapable of loving me.
天哪 费格斯 演技省省上台发挥吧
Goodness, Fergus, save it for the stage, why don't you?
说得太好了
I mean, fabulous speech,
但你把自己放在了过高的地位上
but you put yourself on far too high a pedestal.
事实是 我的确不 以后也不会
The fact remains I do not, will not,
以前也从没爱过任何东西
and have not loved anything ever.
你刚刚说什么
You were saying?
记得我们在那教堂里吗
Remember when we were in that church,
恢复克劳力的人性
making Crowley human,
即将关闭地狱之门
about to close the gates of hell?
你那时可准备好牺牲小我拯救世界了
Well, you sure as hell were ready to die for the greater good then.
是的 迪恩 是你把我拉了回来
Yeah, and, Dean, you pulled me back.
我错了
And I was wrong.
你是对的 萨姆
You were right, Sam.
你早就知道 这个世界没有我们会更好
You knew that this world would be better without us in it.
不不 等等
No, no, no, wait a second.
你在曲解我的话 迪恩
You're twisting my words here, Dean.
为什么 因为我们追踪邪恶并杀之
Why? Because we … we track evil and kill it?
家族事业 是这样吗
The family business? Is that it?
好好回想一下吧 萨姆
Look at the tape, Sam.
是邪恶跟着我们
Evil tracks us.
邪恶摧毁我们身边的一切
And it nukes everything in our vicinity …
我们的家人 朋友
Our family, our friends.
我们该找准自己的位置
It's time we put a proper name to what we really are.
并接受它了
and we deal with it.
等等
Wait a second.
我们不是邪恶的
We are not evil.
听我说
Listen…
我们虽然远称不上完美 但我们是好人
We're far from perfect, but we are good.
你手臂上的东西是邪恶的
That thing on your arm is evil,
但你不是 我不是
but not you, not me.
我害死了鲁迪
I let Rudy die.
那怎么不邪恶
How was that not evil?
我知道自己是什么 萨姆
I know what I am, Sam.
但是你呢…
But who were you when you …
你开车送那男人去出卖灵魂
when you drove that man to sell his soul…
你还威逼查理
or when you bullied Charlie.
害她被杀
into getting herself killed?
为了什么
And to what end?
为了好结果
A-a good end?
正义的结果吗
A just end?
不惜代价去除血印
To remove the mark no matter what the consequences?
萨姆 这怎么不邪恶
Sam, how is that not evil?
我手臂上有这玩意
I have this thing on my arm,
而你就愿意让黑暗入侵世界
and you're willing to let the darkness into the world.
你还甘愿召唤死神
You were also willing to summon death.
以确保你再也不能伤害任何人
to make sure you could never do any more harm.
你叫我来 是因为你知道
You summoned me because you knew.
为了保护你 我什么都会做
I would do anything to protect you.
这不是邪恶 迪恩
That's not evil, Dean.
你不是邪恶的人
That's not an evil man.
你是一个好人 渴望被听到
That is a good man crying to be heard,
在寻找 其他的办法
searching for… some other way.
不 没有其他办法 萨姆
No, there is no other way, Sam.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
好
Good.
好啊
打吧
Fight.
真是荒谬
This is ridiculous.
你爱这个男人吗 罗威娜 真的吗
Do you love this man? Rowena, is it true?
当然是真的
'course it's true.
打招呼吧 奥斯卡
Say hello, Oskar.
罗威娜
Rowena.
即使是你 费格斯
Even for you, Fergus,
这也是新下限了
this is a new low …
残忍 可耻 令人厌恶的新下限
A cruel, shameful, disgusting low.
你要真下手了才叫残忍
It's only cruel if you actually go through with it.
但到了那时…
Though…
谁才是残忍的那个呢
who's the cruel one then?
行了
Okay.
够了 够了
That's enough. Hey, that's enough.
你永远永远不会听到我说
You'll never, ever hear me say.
说你 真正的你
that you … the real you.
不是好人
is anything but good.
但你说得没错
But you're right.
趁你还没伤害到…其他人
Before you hurt… anyone else,
得不惜一切代价阻止你
you have to be stopped at any cost.
我理解
I understand.
动手吧
Do it.
请吧
Please.
你来吧
Do me the honor.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
萨姆 闭上眼睛
Sammy, close your eyes.
等等
Wait.
拿着这些
Take these.
有一天
And one day,
等你找到了回家的路…
when you find your way back…
让这些指引你
let these be your guide.
它们会帮你记起
And they can help you remember.
善是什么
what it was to be good…
爱是什么
what it was to love.
为了家人 你也必须动手 迪恩
It's for family you must proceed, Dean.
你现在这个样子 你变成这样
To be what you are, to become what you've become.
只会玷污他们的记忆
is a stain on their memory.
动手吧
Do it.
不然我自己来
Or I will.
原谅我
Forgive me.
你都长这么大了
You've grown so big.
希望还能给你老罗威娜阿姨一个拥抱
Not too big to give your old auntie Rowena a hug I hope.
希望我没伤到你
Hope I haven't hurt you.
别那么想
Don't think about that one moment.
没事的 奥斯卡
Everything's fine, Oskar.
一切都很好
Everything's fine.
没谁会伤害谁
Nobody's hurting anybody.
再见了 我亲爱的孩子
Goodbye, my sweet wee boy.
[咒语]
你没事吧
You okay?
死不了
I'll live.
你呢
You?
棒极了
Fantastic.
我觉得我刚刚杀了死神
I think I just killed Death.
[咒语]
你觉得那听起来正常吗
That sound right to you?
[咒语]
怎么回事
What is this?
这不可能
This is impossible.
你没这个力量
You're not powerful enough.
做什么
To what?
控制一个无聊的国王和一个乱来的天使吗
Control the likes of a bored king and a wayward angel?
[咒语]
费格斯 恐怕在你漫长的一生中
I'm afraid, Fergus, that in all your long life,
从没见识过一个真有法力的真女巫的本事
you've never seen what a real witch can do with real magic.
我非常高兴
I'm terrifically pleased.
那将是你看见的最后一幕
it's the last thing you'll ever see.
[咒语]
卡西迪奥
Castiel.
不要
Don't.
Do not.
别
Don't!
求你了
Please!
这很好
This is good.
迪恩 这样挺好
Dean, this is good.
你手臂上的血印没了
The … the mark is off your arm.
也没出什么事
Nothing crazy happened.
你拿回了你的宝贝
You get your baby back.
是啊
Yeah.
肯定一切都好着呢
I'm sure everything's perfectly fine.
怎么回事
What?
死神怎么说的来着
What did Death call this?
黑暗
The darkness.
- 上车 - 好
- Get in the car. - Yeah.
走 快走
Let's go, let's go!
迪恩
Dean.
Dean!